myiuhealth.org 2017-12-14

# Privacy Policy | IU Health

Indiana University Health is dedicated to protecting your privacy. We have created the following Web site privacy policy so you can be assured that any information you share with us via iuhealth.org will remain confidential.

###  i. Introduction

IU Health is dedicated to maintaining the highest standards for privacy, security, credibility and reliability. We present this policy to give you a clear understanding of how we operate our Web site and how we handle your personal information.

This privacy policy may be revised periodically. When we make significant changes that affect our collection and use of your personal information or our security practices, we will post a notice on the IU Health home page for 30 days. We recommend that you read our privacy policy whenever you visit our site in case you missed our notice or have not registered for a service or feature of our site previously.

When you visit and navigate our Web site, we will not collect personal information about you unless you provide us that information voluntarily. By "personal information," we mean data that is unique to an individual, such as a name, address, e-mail address or telephone number.

###  ii. Registration

You are always welcome to use the IU Health site without registering or providing any personal information. However, we require you to register for certain services, including our free health e-mails, discussion boards (when available), and other features, including online bill pay. When you use these features, we will clearly disclose what information is required, what information is optional and how that information may be used.

When you register for free e-mails, we require the following personal information: e-mail address, first and last name, zip code, year of birth, gender, marital status and number of children under age 18 living in your household. We also ask you to select a personal password. In addition, we give you the option to provide additional information, including city, state and topics of interest.

We use this information in aggregate form only. In other words, we combine the information with data collected from other individuals to produce anonymous, aggregated statistical information. We collect and use demographic information, such as the percentage of female visitors or the number of visitors of a certain age, in order to improve the content of our site. We also may share this anonymous, aggregated information, which does not identify individuals, with partners or other third parties. In instances where third parties may receive anonymous, aggregated user information collected on our site, our agreements with the third parties, including sponsors, generally provide that the third parties will not use the anonymous, aggregated user information to identify individual users or sell, disclose or provide access to any user information collected on our site that would identify any individual or connect any individual to specific illnesses or conditions.

When you register to use discussion boards, we require that you provide your e-mail address and select a username and password. We use this information only if you violate our terms and conditions for participation in these forums and we have to contact you.

We treat any personal information you give us as confidential. We do not analyze your personal information nor do we collect specific information about your use of our site.

IU Health will not disclose to third parties any identifying personal information gathered from you during registration for e-mails and discussion boards and other features, unless (1) we tell you how your information will be used and you give IU Health specific permission to share this information or (2) IU Health is required to disclose such information by any applicable law or legal process (like a subpoena or court order). Where we disclose identifying personal information to third parties with your authorization, we will require the recipient to use the information only for the purpose provided.

###  iii. Security of Information

IU Health implements security procedures to protect personal information you submit to us from misuse or unauthorized disclosure. The personal information that you submit to us is stored in our secure database behind an electronic firewall. You can access your personal information only by using a password. We encourage you to change your password regularly and not to share it with anyone.

Access to the data within IU Health is limited to a few computer technicians for our site who need to maintain the database and who also use passwords for that access, as well as outside vendors who may occasionally assist us in maintaining and improving our hardware and software tools.

IU Health makes every effort to safeguard your personal information. However, like other Internet sites, we cannot guarantee that it is completely secure from people who might attempt to evade security measures or intercept transmissions over the Internet.

Similarly, we cannot completely ensure the privacy of e-mail communications to and from our site because they are not encrypted and, therefore, not secure. These communications, like most Internet e-mail, could be intercepted without your knowledge and permission, while in transit to or from our site. If you are concerned about your privacy, we suggest that you do not use e-mail to communicate information to us that you consider sensitive.

When you register for IU Health's free health e-mails, your information is not secure during transmission to us.

###  iv. Changing or Deleting Your Personal Information

You can change the personal information in your IU Health profile at any time by clicking on "Edit Profile" on the navigation bar at the top of any page on our site. If you forget your password, click on "Forgot Password?" at the top of any page and we will walk you through the process of resetting your password.

Unsubscribing from our free health e-mails does not delete your personal information from our system, even if you unsubscribe from all e-mails. We will delete your personal registration information from the active and searchable areas of our system at your request. Be aware, however, that it is not feasible for us to remove every electronic record that may contain your data. We cannot remove copies of your information that may exist in records we create as backup in case our main data is lost. We also cannot delete information from anonymous, aggregated databases. This information cannot be linked to you. IU Health maintains and archives all personally identifiable information provided by users. This data is retained in our archives and not deleted.

If you registered for discussion boards and also want that information removed, please note that in your request. Please inform us if you used a different e-mail address or password when registering for discussion boards.

To have your registration information removed, send your request by email. You will receive a confirmation from us.

###  v. Privacy Concerns

If you have any concerns about the security or privacy of your personal identifiable information on the IU Health Web site, please contact us by email or send a written notification to:

IU Health Marketing and Corporate Communications  
Attn: Webmaster  
340 W. 10th St., Suite 5200  
P.O. Box 1367  
Indianapolis, IN 46206

###  vi. E-mails

When you sign up for free health e-mails, IU Health maintains information about your selections only for the purpose of sending you the e-mails. We do not use identifying personal information for any other purpose although it may be included in anonymous, aggregated statistical information.

We will send you only information that you request.

A link for unsubscribing from e-mails is located at the bottom of each e-mail. You also can unsubscribe by using the "Change Profile" link at the bottom of any page on our site. Unsubscribing from e-mails does not delete your personal information from our system, even if you unsubscribe from all e-mails.

###  vii. Discussion Boards

If you are concerned about privacy, use caution when posting messages to our discussion boards. The discussion boards are open to the public so others using these areas on our site can read your posts. Any information you include when participating in discussion boards is available to anyone with Internet access. For example, if you include your e-mail address in a message you post on a discussion board, it is publicly accessible.

IU Health does not collect information posted on our discussion boards.

Discussion boards are monitored from time to time. IU Health reserves the right to remove any posts we feel are inappropriate, contain abusive language or threaten or violate the privacy of our company, sponsors or visitors as provided in our terms and conditions.

###  viii. Cookies

Cookies are small bits of information placed on your computer's hard drive by a Web site. It is a simple text file that helps your browser to remember certain information that the Web site can later retrieve to streamline communication between your browser and the Web site. IU Health does not store this information. Our site can only read the cookies placed on your computer by us. We cannot access any information on your hard drive placed there by you or any other source. IU Health uses cookies for user convenience. The cookie will tell our system certain information so you don't have to fill in the same information each time you visit us.

IU Health uses only benign cookies that have no functionality. This means the cookie cannot do anything to your computer's hard drive and cannot read information from your computer's hard drive.

Cookies also may be used by IU Health on an aggregate basis to track site navigation. This information is not traceable to an individual user. Navigation streams are used to assist us in determining where people go when visiting our site and how long they stay in a particular area. This information is used to improve our site and may be shared with advertisers.

Unlike many other Web sites, IU Health does not use cookies to tailor information that appears during your visit to your preferences or your use of our site.  
If you click on a sponsorship acknowledgment, you will be leaving IU Health and will be directed to the sponsor's site. Be aware that IU Health has no control over the practices of other Web sites. Your computer may receive cookies from other sites and you will not be protected by IU Health's security and privacy policies.  
The cookie feature can be turned off on your browser. For more information on turning off the cookie feature, consult your browser help section. If you choose to turn off cookies, you can still access all areas of our site. Once the cookie feature on your browser is turned off, you might have to "refuse" a cookie each time you encounter one searching our site.

###  ix. IP Addresses

An Internet Protocol (IP) address is a number that is automatically assigned to your computer by your Internet Service Provider (ISP) whenever you access the Internet. This number may be the same each time you access the Internet or it may change. Like other Internet sites, IU Health uses IP addresses to collect aggregate information about numbers of visitors and site usage. The address is logged on our server when your computer requests information from IU Health. However, to allow users to access our site anonymously, your IP address is not linked with personal information about you. IU Health reserves the right, in rare instances, to use IP addresses to identify individuals who threaten our site, service or customers.

###  x. Surveys, Questionnaires and Polls

When you respond to surveys, questionnaires or polls on our site, we may, at times, ask you for demographic information such as your gender or age. This information is collected only as anonymous, aggregated information and is used for statistical purposes. Otherwise, we do not collect or store your personal responses.

###  xi. Contests

When IU Health runs a contest, we may ask for personal information when you enter the contest. If so, we will describe in each instance why we are asking for that personal information and how we plan to use that information.

###  xii. Children

IU Health does not knowingly allow children under the age of 13 to register on our site for any purpose or to access any features that require registration. We require visitors to indicate their year of birth to register. If we learn that we inadvertently have collected identifying personal information from a child under the age of 13, we will promptly delete that information from our system.

###  xiii. Search Functions

We do not collect information about searches that you perform on our site.

###  xiv. Leaving IU Health

This privacy policy applies only as long as you remain on the IU Health Web site. Once you leave IU Health to visit another site, we have no control over your privacy or security issues even if you reached the other site by clicking on a link within IU Health.

Throughout the IU Health Web site, you will see links that can lead you to another site. If you click on an advertisement or sponsorship acknowledgment while you are on IU Health, you will be leaving IU Health and will be directed to the advertiser or sponsor's site. Also, if you click on a link or a "Return to" or "Back to" banner for another Web site, you will be leaving IU Health and will be directed to the linked Web site, IU Health also offers listings of resources that contain links to the Web sites of government agencies and non-profit organizations. If you click on those links, you will be leaving IU Health and will be taken to the Web site of that agency or organization. At times, clicking on a hyperlink within an article will bring up information on another site without warning. In these cases, however, the information will appear in a second, smaller "pop-up" window and the IU Health page will remain clearly visible on your computer screen.

###  xv. Effect of Privacy Policy

This privacy policy is not intended to and does not create any contractual or legal rights in or on behalf of any party.
